RYAN CARVILLE

Full Stack Developer Hunenberg, Zug, Switzerland (Chardonne, Vaud, Switzerland from March 2023) Swiss B permit holder 38 years old

Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

ryancarville@gmail.com +41 79 156 23 29



Accomplished problem solver and creative expert with five years experience building full-stack platforms, scaling projects/platforms, as well as creating and deploying commercial imagery as content. Providing thought partnership, leading with expertise to advise and deliver for clients and employers. Demonstrating high learning agility, changing careers while remaining focused on using the existing mastery of skills in new and different contexts. Comfortable with high levels of ambiguity and self-motivating. Enjoy working in fast-paced environments, am focused on delivering results, and am excited by new and complex challenges.

- Current Tech Stack: TypeScript, React, Serverless (4 years)
- Experienced in the software development lifecycle
- Over 15 years of experience in the advertising industry
- Agile worker who enjoys teams while valuing self-motivated tasks
- MCs in Computer Sciences

EXPERIENCE

June 2020 - July 2022 - **Lead Software Engineer** - AIDONIC - Zug, Switzerland First to market, global web platform for the humanitarian aid space. Providing full transparency and accountability in crowdfunding and last-mile aid distribution using the Stellar Blockchain. Recruited to evaluate MVP and bring to production at scale.

- Re-built most database architectures to allow for maximum efficiency and maintainability
- Expanded and optimized proprietary blockchain-based last mile aide distribution tech stack
- Implemented CI/CD workflows and led the department in feature development and maintenance
- Worked with UI/UX designers to improve overall platform experience and feel
- Close partnership with CEO on tech stack evolution and feature prioritization. Providing modern knowledge of best practices and creative problem solving for business needs
- Winner "CUTTING-EDGE CREATIVITY" Award, Swiss Digital Economy Award 2021 Finalist, Swiss FIntech Finalist, The Europas 2020 Finalist, Top 20 Fintech Startups in Switzerland

Aug 2007 – August 2020 - **Founder/Owner -** Beardy Studios, LLC - New York, NY & San Fransico, CA Procured advertising clients and built long term relationships with them in regards to the design, planning, creation and execution of campaigns. In addition to the creation of advertising content for them, we designed and built online portfolios and e-commerce shops to promote their brand and products.

As a full-stack developer in this role, I worked directly with the clients, or their designers, from start to finish in the design, architecture, user experience, user interface design, and development of the required online platforms.

- Build e-commerce platforms for fashion and real estate brands
- Advised on technology architectures
- Developed working end products which were then deployed to production
- Maintained production sites as needed
- Technologies used: Java, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, REST API's, SQL Databases

Other roles I held were Photographer, Lighting Designer, Art Director, Producer, Retoucher, & Video Editor. In these roles, I worked directly with client creative leadership teams to create brand imagery/video content for ad campaigns, marketing, and/or e-commerce.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF BATH | May 2020 - present [graduation May 2023]

MSc Computer Science

Description of course work and my dissertation topic

Completed a thirteen module course load over the course of two years including Foundations of Computation, Artificial Intelligence, Cyber Security, Intelligent Control and Cognitive Systems, Databases and Cloud and Functional Programming. Currently, I am writing my dissertation on passive user data collection at point-of-sale transactions.

THINKFUL/BLOC | January 2019 - July 2019

Full Stack Developer Track

Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer. Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on

- JavaScript
- Node.js
- React
- Redux
- HTML5
- CSS5
- Algorithms
- Data structures

TEXAS STATE UNIVERSITY | August 2003 - August 2007 **BFA in Digital and Photographic Imaging**

Graduated Cum Laude 3.8 GPA

SKILLS

Tech	Level	Years
TypeScript	***	4
JavaScript	***	9
React	***	5
Node.js	***	3
Python	***	4
Serverless	***	3
MicroServices	**	2
RESTful API's	***	9
Responsive Design	****	6
Agile Frameworks	****	5

LANGUAGES

English - Native German - A2 French - A1

REFERENCES

Upon Request